

Vibha Gupta TCS-Digital System Engineer, TCS Pvt.

Vibhagupta1996@gmail.com

+91-8802962295

February 04, 1996

linkedin.com/in/0496Vibha-Gupta

Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India

Data Scientist with 4 years of professional experience in Life Science Domain, Hands-on in Python, SQL, Statistics and Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Power BI, Open for all challenges with efficient use of my knowledge with active addition of new skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

TATA Consultancy Services Pvt. Ltd.

10/2020 - Present

Noida

- Working as a Data Scientist for a France based pharmaceutical client. Using Python, statistical and ML concepts for efficient analysis.
- Tools and Languages: Python, ML, Statistics, XML, Regression, Pandas, Numpy, GitHub, Jira, Miro.

System Engineer

TATA Consultancy Services Pvt. Ltd.

03/2018 - 09/2020

Bangalore

- Worked as SAP Security Roles & Authorization Administrator for a US based reputed pharmaceutical client & Compleo Scripting automation.

Web Designer and Blog writer, Trainee Dukami Enterprise Pvt. Ltd.

01/2018 - 02/2018

Noida

- Front-end development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Media Query.

Software developer, Trainee Graebert India Software Pvt. Ltd.

08/2017 - 11/2017

Noida

- Worked on company's product "Ares Commander" project development in CAD domain in 3-D solids dimension features.
- Tools: C++, Qt designer, tortoise SVN, vector graphics.

EDUCATION

08/2013 - 05/2017

B.Tech in Computer Science

University Of Delhi

Marks- 87.28%

Senior Secondary, PCM Dehradun Public School, Ghaziabad

04/2012 - 03/2013 Marks-93%

SKILLS & TOOLS

Python Statistics in ML Power BI SQL **EDA** Machine Learning **XML** Github

MANAGEMENT EXPERIENCE

Crisis Management Lead in TCS (08/2018 - Present)

CSR Head of Project in TCS (07/2018 - 06/2019)

PROJECTS & INTERESTS

Data Scientist

- Working as a Data Scientist presently, actively using my knowledge of Python, Statistics, SQL, Machine Learning, Pandas, Numpy, all Regression & classification algorithms, Random Forest, Decision Trees, Gradient boosting EDA, etc.

Data Analysis

- BI Visualization tools: Power BI, Tableau.

ACHIEVEMENTS & CERTIFICATES

Certified in Python for Data Science by IBM(2021) & Kaggle(2022)

Certified in Advanced SQL by Kaggle (2022)

Record of Achievement by openSAP

Intelligent Robotic Process Automation in a nutshell

TCS Digital- Marked as Hi-talent in the organization for Digital technologies (02/2020 - Present)

Certified in AOA (Art of Articulation) with L1 Proficiency.

Certified in SAP security and Authorization (2019)

APPRECIATIONS & AWARDS

Appreciation for good Presentation skills. (2018)

Awards of Excellence and beyond performance in TCS (2021)